<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://eliazonta.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://eliazonta.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-06-14T21:31:20+00:00</updated><id>https://eliazonta.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Why this.</title><link href="https://eliazonta.github.io/blog/2025/why/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why this."/><published>2025-04-01T15:09:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-01T15:09:00+00:00</updated><id>https://eliazonta.github.io/blog/2025/why</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eliazonta.github.io/blog/2025/why/"><![CDATA[<p>So yeah—why this? Why bother starting a blog in 2025, when there are literally millions of them already floating around? I’ve been asking myself the same thing, honestly. But the answer I keep coming back to is simple: I just wanted to.</p> <p>There’s something grounding about having a space to sit down, breathe a bit, and write things out. It’s not really about going viral or building some massive audience. It’s more like—me, my thoughts, and a quiet page. That’s all.</p> <p>Writing gives me space to think. It slows everything down in the best way. Sometimes when I’m typing things out, I realize I didn’t really understand how I felt about something until the words showed up in front of me. That space? That clarity? That’s what I’m here for.</p> <p>So this blog is just that. A place to wind down, reflect, maybe untangle a few thoughts. Nothing fancy, no master plan—just a calm corner of the internet to figure stuff out.</p> <p>Still a work in progress. But so am I.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="random"/><category term="intro"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reasons behind my idea of writing things down.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Master’s degree choice</title><link href="https://eliazonta.github.io/blog/2024/masters/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Master’s degree choice"/><published>2024-07-01T15:09:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-01T15:09:00+00:00</updated><id>https://eliazonta.github.io/blog/2024/masters</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eliazonta.github.io/blog/2024/masters/"><![CDATA[<p>So here’s a little backstory.</p> <p>I studied Computer Science and Engineering at the University of Trento. Great place, solid degree. But honestly, I never just stuck to the “expected path.” I was always the one chasing side projects, new experiences, whatever looked interesting and just a bit out of reach.</p> <p>That mindset led me to some wild and amazing opportunities: Fondazione Bruno Kessler (arguably the <em>top</em> research center in Italy), FZJ Jülich in Germany (aka Europe’s supercomputing powerhouse), a stint at Pirelli, and then all the way to Cornell for my bachelor thesis.</p> <p>And Cornell… that hit different.</p> <p>It’s where I really discovered a passion for maths. Not just in a theoretical way, but in that deep, “this is what I want to wake up and study” kind of way. I started feeling like, yeah, this is what I want to pursue more seriously.</p> <p>The twist? I had already applied for CS master’s programs across Europe. And not just anywhere—TU Delft, Imperial, UCL… some of the best. The kind of places that look great on paper, where your LinkedIn glows just from the name.</p> <p>But most math-heavy master’s programs don’t exactly roll out the red carpet for someone with a CS undergrad. So I had to pivot.</p> <p>And yeah, that meant saying no to some big names, and yes to a lesser-known university that was willing to take me in for what I actually wanted to do. A step down in prestige, maybe, but a step up in alignment with my interests.</p> <p>I’ve always been someone who builds my own path, even if it’s not the clearest or easiest. This was one of those moments. And I’m proud of it.</p> <p>In the end, I’d rather be doing what I love at full speed than stuck on a “safe” track going nowhere I really want to be.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="random"/><category term="intro"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I decided to swich major for my masters, here's why.]]></summary></entry></feed>